{"tossups": [{"question": "Evidence from the Bradford Letter argues that a performance of<em> Cato</em> in this location was a lavish social event, not a celebration of republicanism. In this location, a manual nicknamed the Blue Book was translated into English. Christopher Ludwick developed a type of Pepper Pot Soup at this location, where Baron von Steuben led training drills. For ten points, name this Pennsylvania location where the Continental Army spent the harsh 1777-1778 winter.", "answer": "<b> Valley Forge</b> (prompt on Pennsylvania before read)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Description acceptable. The central figure of this controversy cried \u201cIs there an epidemic of cholera or something?\u201d and \u201cWhat is it, do you have rocket launching pads there?\u201d before trying to explain \u201cThis is the situation I am in \u2013 your guest.\u201d This controversy was the fault of the Los Angeles Police, who were supposedly unable to guarantee that guest\u2019s security while his wife, Nina, and his children were to visit\u201cMain Street, USA\u201d and ride the spinning teacups. For ten points, name this 1959 foreign relations gaffe in which the visiting Soviet premier was denied a visit to the \u201cHappiest Place on Earth,\u201d a California theme park.", "answer": "Nikita<b> Khrushchev</b> being denied a trip to<b> Disney</b>land (accept answers that mention <b>Khrushchev</b> visiting/not being allowed to visit the<b> Disney</b> theme park, but do not accept mentions of\u201c(Walt) Disney World\u201d because that is specifically in Florida and not open for another decade; prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "This city hosted a 1935 exposition which featured the Richard Requa designed Old Globe Theatre. In 1995, Shawn Nelson was arrested after stealing a tank from an armory in this city. This city\u2019s Miramar neighborhood was the original home of the Navy\u2019s TOPGUN program. The USS<em> Midway</em> Museum is located in this city, across from the resort town of Coronado. Balboa Park is located in, for ten points, what Southern California city that borders Chula Vista and Tijuana?", "answer": "<b> San Diego</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "This was the site of a massacre perpetrated by Yamaji Motoharu following victory at the Battle of Lushunkou. In a later conflict, this location was the site of a poorly executed night attack that managed to only disable the<em> Pallada</em> and<em> Retvizan</em>. Togo Heihachiro planned a surprise attack on this location in an attempt to destroy Oskar Stark\u2019s Pacific Fleet on the second day of a war. For ten points, what Manchurian harbor was attacked to mark the beginning of the Russo-Japanese War?", "answer": "<b> Port Arthur</b> (or<b> Lushun</b> City or Port; accept<b> Ryojun</b>; accept<b> Lushunkou</b>; prompt on Manchuria before mentioned; prompt on the Liaodong Peninsula)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This woman\u2019s husband died 18 days after she did, allegedly refusing to eat out of grief. This rival of Lilian Smith was left partially paralyzed after a train accident in Lexington, North Carolina. Frank Butler married this woman after she defeated him in a competition involving 25 targets. Her talent was discovered at age 8 when she downed a squirrel with a bullet to the head. For ten points, name this prominent American sharpshooter, nicknamed \u201cLittle Sure Shot\u201d as a member of Buffalo Bill\u2019s Wild West Show.", "answer": "Annie<b> Oakley</b> (or Phoebe Anne<b> Mosey</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This event was presaged by an Emily Hobhouse \u201copen letter\u201d that asked \u201cis it not our mission to preserve life?\u201d A similar-but-unsuccessful attempt at this event was Benedict XV\u2019s [fifteenth\u2019s] \u201cTruce of God.\u201d A football game at Messines was speculated to have taken place during this event, whose participants crossed No Man\u2019s Land to sing songs and swap rations with each other instead of bullets. For ten points, name this festive event during the winter of 1914 in which German and Allied forces stopped fighting.", "answer": "<b> Christmas ceasefire</b> of World War I (accept descriptions of a<b> truce</b> or any sort of pause in fighting on<b> Christmas</b> 1914)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This government created a service of inspectors called<em> metsuke</em> to investigate corruption. Prior to the rule of this government, its second ruler disobeyed orders and fought the Sanada clan at Ueda Castle [oo-AY-da \u201ccastle\u201d]. It created a policy of alternate attendance between the central court and the domains of each provincial lord. Until the Convention of Kanagawa, this government limited trade with China and Europe to the port city of Nagasaki via the<em> sakoku</em> law. Ieyasu founded, for ten points, what final Japanese shogunate that ruled until the Meiji Restoration?", "answer": "<b> Tokugawa</b> Shogunate (or<b> Tokugawa</b> Bakufu; accept<b> Edo</b> Bakufu or Shogunate; accept <b>Tokugawa</b> or<b> Edo</b> period, era, etc.)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "In a Nikos Kazantzakis novel, this figure meets Vladimir Lenin, Don Quixote and Jesus before sailing to Antarctica. According to another work, this hero and Diomedes jump Dolon at night to extract military information; before going off to fight, this man\u2019s son is thrown in front of a plow to prove his sanity. The plot of a wooden horse is devised by, for ten points, what king of Ithaca and clever hero of the Trojan War whose trip home is described in a Homeric epic?", "answer": "<b> Odysseus</b> (accept<b> Ulysses</b>)", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {}, {"question": "This campaign began with an attack on the post office at Westerplatte. Army groups Pomorze and Poznany were destroyed in the Battle of Bzura during this campaign, in which Marshal Smigly-Ridz called for a retreat to the Romanian Bridgehead. This campaign, which included a false flag attack on a radio station at Gliewitz, benefited from a Soviet invasion as part of the Molotov-Ribbentrop Pact. For ten points, name this invasion that began on September 1, 1939, beginning World War II.", "answer": "Nazi<b> German invasion of Poland</b> (or<b> Nazi</b> German<b> invasion of Poland</b>; accept<b> Fall Weiss</b>; prompt on partial answers; prompt on World War II before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "One of these pieces named for Hohenfriedberg was supposedly written by Frederick the Great. These pieces often include a breakstrain in between trios. Joseph Strauss Sr. wrote one for Joseph Radetzky, and the third movement of Chopin\u2019s<em> Piano Sonata Number 2</em> is a \u201cfuneral\u201d type of this piece. Another one of these pieces contains a trio also known as \u201cLand of Hope and Glory\u201d and often played at graduations. For ten points, name this genre of military music that includes Edward Elgar\u2019s \u201cPomp and Circumstance\u201dpieces and many works by John Philip Sousa.", "answer": "<b> march</b>es", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "After his wife sprained her ankle, this man cancelled his booking for a suite on the<em> Titanic</em>. This man inherited the whiskey manufacturer Old Overholt from his grandfather. This friend and business partner of Andrew Mellon was stabbed four times in the leg with a steel file during an assassination attempt conducted by Alexander Berkman; that event occurred after this man threatened to evict workers who participated in the 1892 Homestead Strike. For ten points, name this founder of an eponymous coke business and chairman of Carnegie Steel.", "answer": "Henry Clay<b> Frick</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This discipline is studied in a sociological way by David Bloor, which argues against its ANT theory. Paul Feyeraband developed a theory of \u201cepistemological anarchism\u201d in describing this discipline. The problem of induction is often studied by philosophers studying this topic to analyze the validity of its findings. Martin Gardner advocated for a \u201cI know it when I see it\u201d standard when discussing how to find false versions of this practice, such as phrenology and homeopathy. For ten points, name this process of organizing knowledge in the form of testable hypotheses and predictions.", "answer": "<b> science</b> (accept word forms)", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Sociology"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>Dozens of ethnic Uyghurs were arrested in this city\u2019s district of Zeytinburnu for alleged connections to Abdulkadir Masharipov\u2019s shooting attack of the Reina night club on New Year\u2019s Day 2017. In 2016, a leader gave a speech in this city blaming \u201cthose in (+) Pennsylvania\u201d for threatening his power. 45 people were killed after an ISIS attack on this city\u2019s airport in June 2016. This city\u2019s Fatih Sultan Mehmet and (*)</b> Bosphorus Bridges were closed during a July 2016 coup attempt against President Recep Tayyip Erdogan [AIRD-oh-wan]. For ten points, name this largest city in Turkey.", "answer": "<b> Istanbul</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b>This leader\u2019s policies were based on a research paper of Emilio Sanfuentes known as El Ladrillo, or \u201cthe brick.\u201d This leader used a car bombing in Washington D.C. to eliminate</b> <b>the ambassador Orlando Letelier. The (+)</b> <b>Rettig Report investigated the excesses of this</b> <b>man and was compiled by his successor, Patricio Aylwin. This man\u2019s DINA secret police spearheaded the Operation (*)</b> Condor campaign to disappear political dissidents, and he liberalized his economy with the help of the Chicago Boys. For ten points, name this CIA-backed Chilean dictator who overthrew Salvador Allende in 1973.", "answer": "Augusto<b> Pinochet</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>Two men thought to be August Heinrich and a self portrait of the artist contemplate this object in a painting by Caspar David Friedrich. The scientifically accurate depiction of</b> <b>this object by Ludovico Cigoli and Adam Elsheimer as (+)</b> <b>rough rather than smooth is</b> <b>thought to be influenced by the</b><em><b> Sidereus Nuncius</b></em><b> of Galileo. This object was photographed partially obscured rising over (*) </b> Half Dome in Yosemite National Park by Ansel Adams. For ten points, name this object which Vincent van Gogh showed as a yellow crescent in his<em> Starry Night</em>.", "answer": "Earth\u2019s<b> moon</b> (accept<b> Luna</b>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "For ten points, name this US president who served between Grover Cleveland\u2019s terms.", "answer": "<b> B</b>enjamin<b> Harrison</b> (prompt on Harrison)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>One of this man\u2019s students, Mabel Hubbard, was the daughter of the first head of the National Geographic Society. Old Order Mennonites originally outlawed the most famous innovation by this man, who once worked in the (+) Volta Labaratory. After Charles Guiteau shot President Garfield, this man was tasked with creating a (*) </b>metal detector to find the bullet. He is most famous for developing an object that some historians allege was actually invented by Elisha Gray. That technology was first used when this man told his assistant, Thomas Watson, \u201cCome here-I want to see you.\u201d For ten points, name this inventor of the telephone.", "answer": "Alexander Graham<b> Bell</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}